

Yahaya Muhammd Bello

Frontend Web Developer

- **→** +2349039402857 💌 mbyahya2579@gmail.com 🔰 +234903; 🕈 Maiduguri, Borno State, 600001 Maiduguri

Education

Primary School

Jan 2008 - Jun 2014

El-kanemi is the lead of all private schools in the city, offering El-Kanemi Primary School, Maiduguri

standard education through innovative teaching and standard teaching method with modern learning facilities that makes education easy for students.

Website Link:

https://www.elkanemicollege.com/

Secondary School

Khalid Bin Walid Secondary School, Maiduguri

Khalid Bin Walid is among the best private schools in the city, with strict rules and regulations, that guide their students towards achieving the desired goal.

Undergraduate

Nov 2020 - Present

Borno State University, Maiduguri

university's senate building was inaugurated by Muhammadu Buhari with over 20 departments. The pioneer and current Vice Chancellor Borno State University was established in 2016. It has five faculties of the university is Prof. Umar Kyari Sandabe. In June 2021, the the current President of Nigeria.

Employment

Frontend Web Developer

Jun 2022 - Present

Albert Einstein College of Medicine, Remote I am responsible for:

- Optimizing the user experience.
- Using frontend technologies to bring concepts to life.
 - Developing and maintaining the user interface.
 - implementing design on mobile websites
- Creating tools that improve site interaction regardless of the
- Managing software workflow.

Personal details

January 3rd, Date of birth

Maiduguri, Borno State Place of birth

Gender

Male

Nationality

Nigerian

Oct 2014 - Jul 2020

Civil status Unmarried

Website

upwork.com/freelancers/~010 ec93f61182d074a

muhammad-bello-488159188 linkedin.com/in/yahaya-LinkedIn

Skills

HTML5 & CSS3

JavaScript

jQuery

Bootstrap

React Js

Material-UI

Adobe XD

Git & GitHub

I consent to the processing of my personal data for the purpose of recruitment for the position to which I am applying.

Profile

believe that that my strong technical experience will make me a very good candidate. The key strength that I posses for success in this I'm a Frontend Web Developer with 5+ years of experience, and I includes: self-motivation, experience in cash activities, result oriented mindset and analytical skills.

ook forward to hearing from you, detailed information to support my I will appreciate an opportunity to discuss my candidacy further and potentiality as a credible candidate is clearly stated in upwork and linkedin profile.

Thank you for your approval in anticipation.

Courses

Galaxy Institute of Information Technology Provider: Galaxy Institute of Information Technology

In this course I cover the concept of Backend Web Development with PHP and MySQL.

Jun 2022 Certificate of Language Ability **Provider: Emmersion**

including some academic and professional topics. They can handle a familiar situation with an unexpected complication. They can talk in detail and in an organized way about events and experience in conversations about familiar topics that go beyond everyday life, Ability Description Individuals at this level can participate in various time frames.

Jun 2022 Google Analytics Individual Qualification

Provider: Google Analytics Individual Qualification

The Google Analytics Individual Qualification (IQ) is a demonstration of proficiency in Google Analytics that is available to any individual who has passed the Google Analytics IQ exam Jun 2022 **Google Analytics for Beginner**

Provider: Google Analytics Academy

course also demonstrate how to analyze basic Audience, Acquisition, Google Analytics for Beginners shows new users how to create an account, implement tracking code, and set up data filters. It also interface and reports, and set up dashboards and shortcuts. The and Behavior reports, and set up goals and campaign tracking. practically demonstrate how to navigate the Google Analytics

Certificates

Jun 2022 At the end of this course I get certificate of completion of Backend Provider: Galaxy Institute of Information Technology Web Development with PHP and MySQL. Web Development (Backend Track)

I consent to the processing of my personal data for the purpose of recruitment for the position to which I am applying.

Search Engine Optimization

CSS3

Languages

English

Hobbies

■ Traveling

Apr 2018

- Basketball
- Coding

Provider: Emmersion

including some academic and professional topics. They can handle a familiar situation with an unexpected complication. They can talk in detail and in an organized way about events and experience in conversations about familiar topics that go beyond everyday life, Ability Description Individuals at this level can participate in various time frames.

Google Analytics Individual Qualification

Jun 2023

The Google Analytics Individual Qualification (IQ) is a demonstration of proficiency in Google Analytics that is available to any individual Provider: Google Analytics Individual Qualification

who has passed the Google Analytics IQ exam

Google Analytics for Beginner Provider: Google Analytics Academy

Jun 2022

course also demonstrate how to analyze basic Audience, Acquisition, Google Analytics for Beginners shows new users how to create an account, implement tracking code, and set up data filters. It also interface and reports, and set up dashboards and shortcuts. The and Behavior reports, and set up goals and campaign tracking. practically demonstrate how to navigate the Google Analytics